Marília Braz

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Sao Paulo | Phone: +55 19 99652-7795

Email: marilia.andrad@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/marilia-braz/

GitHub: https://github.com/mariliabraz

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a background in Biosystems Engineering and a transition to technology through the Women Can Code program. Over 4 years of experience in frontend development with React applications. Familiar with projects using agile methodology, committed to delivering clean code, accessible, and responsive interfaces.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer 2022-Present Prime IT - Farfetch Porto, PT

Initially responsible for building an application using vanilla JavaScript, replacing an old spreadsheet-based process. Rebuilt the application with React as it scaled. Working in a data analysis-focused team, now leading training for the newest web developer on the team.

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed and maintained the first application, using JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap and CSS.
- Developed and maintained the second application, rebuilt with React and SCSS.
- Integrated backend services through **Firebase**.

Frontend Developer 2020-2022 Venturus - Ingenico Campinas, BR

Started as a Junior Frontend Developer, working in a Scrum team for a Latin America project. Promoted to Mid Frontend Developer due to demonstrated expertise and commitment, and selected to work on an international project in a SAFe-based team.

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed and maintained frontend applications using **React**, **Redux-Toolkit**, **TypeScript** and **Gatsby**.
- Handled data fetching and API Integration through REST and GraphQL APIs.
- Merged new features based on **code review** request.
- Implemented tests using Jest and Cypress

EDUCATION

Postgraduate in Software Engineering: PUC Minas 2022 - 2023 **Bachelor of Biosystems Engineering**: University of Sao Paulo (USP) 2013 - 2018

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Key Skills: Cross-team collaboration, communication, frontend development, web development, agile teams

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, SCSS, Javascript, React, JSX, Typescript, Bootstrap, Redux-Toolkit, React Hooks, GraphQL, Gatsby, API REST, GitLab, GitHub, i18n, Jest, Cypress